<codeTemplate version="3.4.1">
  <id>4cb42e06-7c9a-4fd2-bcb5-b9f4053a9c19</id>
  <name>Get Segments After a Particular Segment</name>
  <revision>1</revision>
  <lastModified>
    <time>1508796287930</time>
    <timezone>America/New_York</timezone>
  </lastModified>
  <type>FUNCTION</type>
  <contextSet>
    <delegate>
      <contextType>DESTINATION_FILTER_TRANSFORMER</contextType>
      <contextType>SOURCE_RECEIVER</contextType>
      <contextType>SOURCE_FILTER_TRANSFORMER</contextType>
      <contextType>DESTINATION_DISPATCHER</contextType>
      <contextType>DESTINATION_RESPONSE_TRANSFORMER</contextType>
    </delegate>
  </contextSet>
  <code>/**
	Returns an array of segments with the specified name that come after a given segment in the message.
*/
/*
	Author: Nick Rupley
	Date Modified: 2/13/2013
	getSegmentsAfter: Returns an array of segments with the specified name that come after a given segment in the message.

	Arguments
	---------
		Required
		--------
			root:			The root HL7Message node of the message, or the parent of the segment node.
			startSeg:		The segment AFTER which to start collecting segments.
			segName:		The name (String or RegExp) of the segments you want to collect.

		Optional
		--------
			consecutiveInd:	If true, indicates that the segments are expected to come directly after startSeg. 
							If false, segments are collected until another segment with the same name as startSeg is encountered.
							Defaults to false.
			stopSegNames:	An array of segment names that, when encountered, stop the collection of segments.
*/

function getSegmentsAfter(root, startSeg, segName, consecutiveInd, stopSegNames) {
	function test(str) {
		return segName instanceof RegExp ? segName.test(str) : segName === str;
	}

	// The index to start collection is the next one up from the starting segment
	var index = startSeg.childIndex()+1;
	// The return array
	var out = [];
	// Boolean placeholder to stop iteration
	var done = false;
	// Object that will contain all of the stopSegNames strings, bound to a truthy value (1)
	var stopNames = {};
	// Indicates whether we have any stop segments
	var stopNamesInd = false;
	// If stopSegNames is defined
	if (stopSegNames !== undefined &amp;&amp; stopSegNames !== null) {
		// Set our indicator to true
		stopNamesInd = true;
		// Add each string in the array to our object
		for each (name in stopSegNames)
			stopNames[name] = 1;
	}

	// Iterate through each child in the root, starting at the segment after startSeg, and
	// ending at the final segment, or when the done flag is set to true.
	while (index &lt; root.children().length() &amp;&amp; !done) {
		// If a stop segment is encountered, stop iteration
		if (stopNamesInd &amp;&amp; root.children()[index].name().toString() in stopNames)
			done = true;
		// If a segment with the same name as startSeg is encountered, stop iteration
		else if (root.children()[index].name().toString() == startSeg.name().toString() &amp;&amp; !consecutiveInd)
			done = true;
		// If we&apos;re only collecting consecutive segments and we encounter a segment with a name other than segName, stop iteration
		else if (!test(root.children()[index].name().toString()) &amp;&amp; consecutiveInd)
			done = true;
		// If all previous tests passed, and the current segment has a name of segName, then add it to our array
		else if (test(root.children()[index].name().toString()))
			out.push(root.children()[index]);
		// Increment our index counter
		index++;
	}

	// Return the output array
	return out;
}</code>
</codeTemplate>